

Experienced front-end software engineer with a passion for building accessible and user-friendly web products. I'm dedicated to creating elegant solutions that enhance the user experience

alex.voievudko@gmail.com +34 638 115 293 Barcelona, Spain <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Portfolio</u> <u>GitHub</u>

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Front-End Developer • ZeptoLab • Oct 2022 - current

- Developed an internal tool to track Google Play and App Store ratings, as well as crash/ANR rates, using Nest.js, Postgres, Prisma, and React (all fully typed with TypeScript).
- Built and launched <u>careers.zeptolab.com</u>, a new website for job openings, using **Gatsby.js** and styled-components (also in **TypeScript**), enhancing the candidate experience and streamlining the hiring process.
- Currently developing internal tools for the Player XP and other teams using TypeScript, React, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Nest.js, Material UI, Chakra UI, improving team productivity and enabling data-driven decision-making.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver cutting-edge solutions that meet business objectives and exceed user expectations.

### Player XP Team Lead • Tilting Point • Dec 2020 - Jul 2022

- Built and led high-performing teams, delivering exceptional player experiences.
- Aligned team goals with business objectives and industry best practices.
- Implemented technology and automation, resulting in cost savings and improved player satisfaction.
- Mentored new team members and drove team success.

## Project Manager • Plarium • Aug 2019 - Dec 2022

- Led ChatBot project to improve Customer Support productivity.
- Implemented machine learning tool for Google Play reviews, increasing processed reviews by 66%.
- Gathered project requirements with stakeholders.
- Established optimized work schedules using agile methodologies.

# Community Management General Lead • Plarium • Aug 2019 - Dec 2022

- Assisted the director in leading and managing a team of 53 members, promoting collaboration and teamwork.
- Improved team processes, increasing productivity, efficiency, and customer satisfaction.
- Developed and implemented strategic plans for department growth and success.
- Provided regular reports and analysis on departmental performance to facilitate data-driven decision-making.

### **SKILLS**

### Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML, CSS, Sass, React Native, Next.js, Gatsby.js, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Chakra UI

#### **Back-end & Databases**

Nest.js, Express.js, Prisma, Firebase, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, GitHub, Docker, Webpack, Storybook, Figma

### **EDUCATION**

Ivan Franko National University of Lviv

Specialist of General Physics